

# CONTACT

- moel-huijskens.azurewebsites.net
- ✓ roelh96@gmail.com
- P Den Haag, Ypenburg
- linkedin [link]

# **SKILLS**

- Python
- R
- SQL/Postgres/Mongo/Redis
- Software Engineering
- Azure
- Linux
- Statistics
- Ansible
- Presenting

# LANGUAGES

- Dutch (Mother Language)
- English (Fluent)

# ROEL HUIJSKENS

# SOFTWARE/DATA/DEVOPS ENGINEER

## **PROFILE**

Highly motivated Software/DevOps Engineer with a strong background in applied statistics and several years of experience working in the financial sector. Acquired substantial practical experience implementing data tooling solutions in an organization with strict regulatory standards. My most productive days are spent tackling complex problems by implementing maintainable and flexible solutions. I highly value knowledge sharing within organizations and constructive collaboration. Always curious and learning new technical skills.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **APG Asset Management**

2022 - PRESENT

**Devops Engineer** 

- Developed and maintained tools for building data analytics applications using R/Python on Posit and custom APIs (e.g., Bloomberg Data License Interface).
- Assisted the business in implementing best practices for software/application development, including CI/CD and testing.
- Co-created a chatbot (OpenAI + RAG) to answer questions regarding the documentation of our team.
- Co-owner of the Python community, promoting best practices and knowledge sharing.

#### **Createment** 2020 - 2022

**IT Trainee** 

- Completed an extensive 2-month bootcamp focusing on software design patterns, Java, Scrum, and data modeling.
- Implemented a process for delivering databases to business users.
- Assisted users in building and deploying their Qlik, R, Python applications, and Alteryx workflows.

#### Statistics Netherlands (CBS)

2019 - 2020

Research Intern

- Completed my research master's thesis on non-probability sampling in official statistics.
- Successfully completed the European Master in Official Statistics (EMOS) program.

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

#### **Azure**

- Azure Fundamentals [Link]
- Azure Al Fundamentals [Link]
- Azure Data Scientist Assoc [Link]

#### DeepLearning.ai

- Machine Learning [Link]
- Deep Learning [Link]

#### **Alteryx**

• Alteryx Designer Core [Link]

#### **Datacamp**

• Python Developer [Link]

#### Scrum.org

• Prof Scrum Master I [Link]

#### **EDUCATION**

### **Master Applied Statistics**

2018-2020

**Utrecht University** 

- Selective Research Master with a strong focus on statistical methodology
- Thesis: Correcting Selectivity of Non-probability Samples by Means of Sample Matching
- · Graduated Cum Laude
- · Key Courses:
  - Mathematical Statistics
  - Multivariate Statistics
  - Statistical Learning (ML)
  - Statistical Computing with R
  - Bayesian Statistics

See my website for more info

# **Bachelor Psychology**

2015-2018

VU Amsterdam

- Bachelor program psychology with a specialization in statistics/research methodology and behavioral genetics.
- Thesis: Power Analysis of Detecting G-E Correlation using the Classical Twin Model Extended with Polygenic Scores (awarded best thesis of my cohort: <a href="mailto:certificate">certificate</a> [Link]).
- GPA: 8
- · Key Courses:
  - Statistics
  - R programming
  - Psychometrics
  - Research Methodology
  - Behavioural Genetics

See my website for more info